What do you see?
ماذا ترون؟
Most of you see a barbershop,
يرى معظمكم صالون الحلاقة،
but I see an opportunity:
ولكنني أرى فرصة:
an opportunity for health,
فرصة من أجل الصحة.
an opportunity for health equity.
فرصة من أجل تطبيق المساواة الصحة،
For black men, the barbershop is not just a place
بالنسبة للرجال ذوي البشرة السوداء، صالون الحلاقة ليس مجرد مكان
where you get your hair cut or your beard trimmed.
حيث يتم فيه قص شعركم أو تقصير لحيتكم.
No, it's much more than that.
لا، إنه أكثر من ذلك بكثير.
Historically, the barbershop has been a safe haven for black men.
تاريخياً، كان صالون الحلاقة ملاذاً آمناً للرجال السود.
It's a place where we go for friendship,
إنه المكان الذي نذهبُ إليه من أجل الصداقة،
solidarity and solace.
والتضامن والسلوان.
It's a place where we go to get away from the stress
إنه المكان حيث نذهب للابتعاد عن التوتر والإجهاد
of the grind of work
نتيجة قسوة العمل
and sometimes home life.
وأحياناً الحياة المنزلية.
It's a place where we don't have to worry
إنه المكان حيث لا يتوجب علينا أن نقلق
about how we're being perceived by the outside world.
حول كيف يُنظرُ لنا من قبل العالم الخارجي.
It's a place where we don't feel threatened,
إنه المكان حيث لا نشعرُ فيه بالتهديد،
or threatening.
أو العداء.
It's a place of loyalty and trust.
إنه مكان الولاء والصدق.
For that reason,
لهذا السبب،
it's one of the few places where we can fearlessly be ourselves
فإنه أحدُ الأماكن القليلة حيث يمكن لنا أن نكون كما نحن دون خوف
and just ... talk.
وفقط... التحدث.
The talk, the shop talk, the conversation,
الحديث وحديث الصالون والمحادثات،
that is the essence of the black barbershop.
هي ما تشكل جوهر صالون الحلاقة للسود.
I can remember going to the barbershop with my dad as a kid.
يمكنني تذكر الذهاب إلى صالون الحلاقة كطفل مع والدي.
We went to Mr. Mike's barbershop every other Saturday.
كنا نذهب إلى صالون حلاقة السيد مايك يوم السبت كل أسبوعين.
And like clockwork, the same group of men would be there
وكما هي ساعة العمل، تكون هناك نفس مجموعة الرجال
every time we went,
في كل مرة نذهب فيها،
either waiting on their favorite barber
أكان الإنتظار لحلاقهم المفضل
or just soaking up the atmosphere.
أو مجرد التمتع بالجو العام.
I can remember the jovial greeting that warmly welcomed us
يمكنني تذكر التحيات المرحة التي كانت ترحب بنا بحرارة
every time we went.
في كل مرة كنا نذهبُ فيها.
"Hey Rev," they would say to my dad.
"أهلاً ريف"، كانوا يقولون لوالدي،
He's a local pastor, and they treated him like a celebrity.
كان قسيسياً محلياً، وكانوا يعاملونه كشخص مشهور.
"Hey young fella, how you doing?"
"أهلاً بالرفيق الصغير، كيف أنت؟"
they would say to me,
كانوا يقولون لي،
making me feel just as special.
ويجعلوني أشعر كم أنا مميز.
I remember the range of the conversations was immense.
أتذكر كانت مدى المحادثاث واسعة.
The men would talk about politics and sports and music
كان يتحدثُ الرجال عن السياسة والرياضة والموسيقى
and world news, national news,
وأخبار العالم والأخبار المحلية الوطنية،
neighborhood news.
وأخبار الجيران.
There was some talk about women
وكان هناك بعض الحديث عن النساء
and what it was like to be a black man in America.
وكيف كان الرجل الأسود في أمريكا.
But many times they also talked about health.
ولكن تحدثوا أيضاً حول الصحة في مرات عديدة.
The conversations about health were lengthy and deep.
كانت المحادثاث عن الصحة طويلة وعميقة.
The men often recounted their doctor's recommendations
كان يروي الرجال أحياناً توصيات أطبائهم
to cut salt in their diet
لخفض كمية الملح في طعامهم
or to eat less fried foods
أو التقليل من تناول الأطعمة المقلية
or to stop smoking
أو التوقف عن التدخين
or to reduce stress.
أو الحد من التوتر.
They talked about the different ways you could reduce stress,
تحدثوا حول الطرق المختلفة التي يمكنهم فيها التقليل من التوتر،
like simplifying one's love life --
مثل تبسيط الحياة العاطفية للكل منا --
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
all ways to treat high blood pressure.
كل الوسائل لمعالجة ارتفاع ضغط الدم.
There's a lot of talk about high blood pressure in the barbershop.
هناك الكثير من الأحاديث حول ارتفاع ضغط الدم في صالون الحلاقة.
That's because almost 40 percent of black men have it.
إذ أن 40% من الرجال السود تقريباً يعانون منه.
That means that almost every single black man
وهذا يعني أن كل رجل أسود تقريباً
either has high blood pressure
لدية إمّا ارتفاع ضغط الدم
or knows a black man who has it.
أو يعرف رجلاً اسوداً يعاني منه.
Sometimes, those conversations in the barbershop
في بعض الأحيان، تلك المحادثات في صالون الحلاقة
would be about what happens when high blood pressure
تكون حول ماذا يجري عندما ارتفاع ضغط الدم
is not adequately addressed.
لا يتم علاجه بطريقة مناسبة.
"Say, did you hear about Jimmy? He had a stroke."
"أقول: هل سمعتم عن جيمي؟ لديه جلطة دماغية."
"Did you hear about Eddie? He died last week.
هل سمعتم عن إيدي؟ لقد توفي الأسبوع الماضي.
Massive heart attack.
سكتة قلبية قاتلة.
He was 50."
كان في الخمسين من العمر."
More black men die from high blood pressure than from anything else,
يموتُ المزيد من الرجال السود بسبب ضغط الدم المرتفع أكثرمن أي شيء آخر،
even though decades of medical wisdom and science have demonstrated
على الرغم من أن عقوداً من الحكمة الطبية والعلم قد برهنت
that death from high blood pressure can be prevented
أنه يمكن الوقاية من الموت نتيجة ارتفاع ضغط الدم
with timely diagnosis and appropriate treatment.
مع التشخيص في الوقت المناسب والعلاج الملائم.
So why is high blood pressure so differentially deadly for black men?
إذا لم يكون رتفاع ضغط الدم مميتا بدرجات مختلفة لدي الرجال السود؟
Because too often, high blood pressure is either untreated
لأنه في الغالب، إمّا لا يتم علاج ارتفاع ضغط الدم
or under-treated in black men,
أو لا يتم علاجه بالشكل الكافي بينهم،
in part because of our lower engagement with the primary healthcare system.
في جزء منه بسبب انخفاض مشاركتنا في نظام الرعاية الصحية الأساسية.
Black men, in particular those with high blood pressure,
الرجال السود ولا سيما هؤلاء الذين يعانون من ضغط دم مرتفع،
are less likely to have a primary care doctor
هم أقل احتمالاً أن يكون لديهم طبيب عائلة
than other groups.
من المجموعات الأخرى.
But why?
لكن لماذا؟
Some of our earliest research on black men's health
بعض من بحوثنا السابقة حول صحة الرجال السود
revealed that for many, the doctor's office is associated with fear,
كشفت أنه للعديد منهم، فإن مكتب الطبيب يرافقه الخوف،
mistrust,
وعدم الثقة،
disrespect,
وعدم الإحترام،
and unnecessary unpleasantness.
والأحداث غير السارة التي لا ضرورة لها.
The doctor's office is only a place that you go when you don't feel well.
مكتب الطبيب هو مجرد مكان تذهبون إليه عندما لا تكونون بخير.
And when you do go, you might wait for hours
وعندما تفعلون، لربما تنتظرون ساعات
only to get the run-around
للحصول فقط على وقت صعب
and to be evaluated by a stoic figure in a white coat
والتقييم من قبل شخصية رواقية في معطف أبيض
who only has 10 minutes to give you
لديها فقط عشر دقائق ليعطيها لكم
and who doesn't value the talk.
والذي لا يُقدر الحديث.
So it's no wonder that some men don't want to be bothered
لذلك لا عجب أن بعض الرجال لا يرغبون في أن تتم مضايقتهم
and skip going to the doctor altogether,
وينصرفون عن الذهاب إلى الطبيب تماماً،
especially if they feel fine.
خاصة إذا شعروا بأنهم بخير.
But herein lies the problem.
لكن هنا تكمن المشكلة.
You can feel just fine
يمكنك أن تشعر أنك بخير
while high blood pressure ravages your most vital organs.
بينما يتلفُ ارتفاع ضغط الدم أعضاؤك الأكثر حيوية.
This is Denny Moe,
هذا هو ديني مو،
owner of Denny Moe's Superstar Barbershop in Harlem.
صاحب صالون الحلاقة الناجح ديني مو في هارلم.
I've been lucky enough to have Denny as my barber for the last eight years.
كنت محظوطاً بما فيه الكفاية ليكون ديني حلاقي لمدة ثماني سنوات الأخيرة.
He said to me once,
قال لي ذات مرة،
"Hey Doc, you know,
"يا دكتور، أتعلم،
lots of black men trust their barbers more than they trust their doctors."
يثق الكثير من الرجال السود بحلاقيهم أكثر من ثقتهم بأطبائهم."
This was stunning to me,
كان ذلك مذهلاً بالنسبة لي،
at first,
في البداية،
but not so much when you think about it.
لكن ليس كثيراً عندما تفكرون في ذلك.
Black men have been with their current barbers
كان الرجال السود مع حلاقيهم الحاليين
on average as long as I've been with Denny,
في المتوسط ما دمتُ كنتُ مع ديني
about eight years.
نحو ثماني سنوات.
And black men see their barbers about every two weeks.
ويرى الرجال السود حلاقيهم كل أسبوعين تقريباً.
Not only do you trust your barber with your look and with your style,
فلستم فقط تثقون بحلاقيكم بالنسبة إلى مظهركم وطريقة أناقتكم،
but you also trust him with your secrets and sometimes your life.
يمكنكم أيضاً الوثوق به مع كل أسراركم وفي بعض الأحيان بحياتكم.
Denny, like many barbers, is more than just an artist,
ديني، مثل العديد من الحلاقيين، هو أكثر من مجرد فنان،
a businessman and confidant.
رجل أعمال وصديق حميم.
He's a leader and a passionate advocate for the well-being of his community.
إنه زعيم ومناصر متحمس من أجل رفاهية مجتمعه.
The very first time I walked into Denny Moe's shop,
في المرة الأولى التي دخلتُ فيها صالون حلاقة ديني مو،
he wasn't just cutting hair.
لم يكن فقط يقص الشعر.
He was also orchestrating a voter registration drive
كان أيضاً ينظم حملة لتسجيل الناخبين
to give a voice to his customers and his community.
لإعطاء الصوت لزبائنه ومجتمعه.
With this kind of activism,
مع هذا النوع من النشاط السياسي والإجتماعي،
and community investment that typifies the black barbershop,
وتوظيف المجتمع الذي يجسد صالون الحلاقة الخاص بالسود،
of course the barbershop is a perfect place
صالون الحلاقة هو بالتأكيد المكان المثالي
to talk about high blood pressure and other health concerns in the community.
للحديث عن ارتفاع ضغط الدم والإهتمامات والمخاوف الصحية الأخرى في المجتمع.
First, the barbershop is not a medical setting,
أولاً، صالون الحلاقة هو ليس محيطاً طبياً،
and so it doesn't have all the negative psychological baggage
وليس لدية كذلك كل النظريات النفسية السلبية
that comes along with that.
التي ترافق ذلك.
When you're in a barbershop,
عندما تكونون في صالون الحلاقة،
you're in your territory, and you're among friends
أنتم في منطقتكم، وبين أصدقائكم
who share your history,
الذين يشاركونكم تاريخكم،
your struggle and your health risks.
ونضالكم والمخاطر الصحية التي تعانون منها.
Second, because the barbershop is a place of connection,
ثانياً، لأن صالون الحلاقة هو مكان للتواصل،
loyalty and trust,
والولاء والثقة،
it's a place where you're more open to have a conversation about health
فهو المكان حيثُ تكونون فيه أكثر انفتاحاً لإجراء محادثات حول الصحة
and especially about high blood pressure.
وخصوصاً حول ارتفاع ضغط الدم.
After all,
بعد كل هذا،
conversations about high blood pressure have all the elements of great shop talk:
لدى المحادثات حول ارتفاع الضغط كل عناصر حديث الصالون البارزة:
stress and high blood pressure,
التوتر وارتفاع ضغط الدم،
food and high blood pressure,
الغذاء وارتفاع ضغط الدم،
relationships and high blood pressure,
العلاقات وارتفاع ضغط الدم،
and yes, what it's like to be a black man in America
ونعم، كيف يبدو أن تكون رجلاً أسوداً في أمريكا
and high blood pressure.
وارتفاع ضغط الدم.
But you can do more than just talk about high blood pressure
لكن يمكنكم القيام بأكثر من مجرد الحديث حول ارتفاع ضغط الدم
in the barbershop.
في صالون الحلاقة.
You can concretely take action.
يمكنكم اتخاذ إجراءات ملموسة.
Here we have an opportunity to partner with the Denny Moe's of the world
لدينا هنا فرصة مشاركة مع عالم ديني مو
and empower communities to address the health inequities
وتمكين المجتمعات لمعالجة التفاوت الصحي
that uniquely affect it.
الذي تؤثر عليه بشكل فريد.
When high blood pressure screening expanded from clinics and hospitals
عندما توسع فحص ارتفاغ ضغط الدم من العيادات والمستشفيات
to communities in the 1960s and '70s,
إلى المجتمعات في سنوات الستينات والسبعينات
black physicians like Dr. Eli Saunders in Baltimore
كان الأطباء السود مثل د. إيلي سوندرز في بالتيمور
and Dr. Keith Ferdinand in New Orleans
ود. كيث فريدناند في نيو اورلينز
were at the forefront of bringing health promotion to community hubs
كانا في الطليعة لجلب التعزيز الصحي لمراكز المجتمع
in urban black neighborhoods.
في أحياء المناطق المدنية للسود.
These pioneers paved the way for my professional journey
مهد هؤلاء الرواد الطريق من أجل رحلتي المهنية
with barbershops and health,
مع صالونات الحلاقة والصحة،
which began in Chicago in medical school.
التي بدأت في شيكاغو في المدرسة الطبية.
The very first research project that I worked on as a medical student
مشروع البحث الأول الذي اشتغلتُ عليه كطالب طب
was to help design healthcare interventions
كان في المساعدة في تصميم برامج تدخلات الرعاية الصحية
that would appeal to black men.
التي يسعى إليها الرجال السود.
We conducted about a dozen focus groups
أجرينا حوالي دزينة من مجموعات التركيز
with a broad cross-section of black men,
على شريحة واسعة من الرجال السود،
and we learned that for them,
وعلمنا أنه بالنسبة لهم،
being healthy was as much about being perceived as healthy
كونهم أصحاء يعني أن ينظر إليهم كأصحاء
as it was about feeling healthy,
أكثر من شعورهم بأنهم أصحاء،
and that feeling good went hand in hand with looking good.
ويأتي الشعور الجيد جنباً إلى جنب مع المظهر الجيد.
This work led to the development of Project Brotherhood,
قاد هذا العمل إلى تطوير "مشروع الأخوية،"
a community clinic founded by Dr. Eric Whitaker
عيادة الصحة المجتمعية التي تم تأسيسها من قبل د. إريك وايتاكر
that provided tailored healthcare to black men.
التي قدمت الرعاية الصحية المصممة للرجال السود.
Part of this tailored care
جزء من هذه الرعاية المصممة
involved having a barber on the premises
انطوت على وجود حلاق في أماكن العمل
to reward the men who came for needed healthcare
لمكافأة الرجال الذين حضروا للرعاية الصحية المحتاجة
with a free haircut,
مع قصة شعر مجانية،
to let the men know that we, too, valued how they looked
والسماح للرجال ليعرفوا أننا أيضاً قدّرنا مظهرهم
as well as how they felt,
بقدر اهتمامهم بما يشعرون به،
and that what was important to them was also important to us.
وما كان مهماً بالنسبة إليهم كان مهماً بالنسبة إلينا.
But while there's only one Project Brotherhood,
لكن بينما يوجد هناك مشروع مجتمع واحد،
there are thousands of black barbershops
هناك الآلاف من صالونات الحلاقة للسود
where the intersection of health and haircuts can be cultivated.
حيث يمكن استثمار ملتقى الصحة وقص الشعر.
The next stop on my journey was Dallas, Texas,
كانت المحطة التالية من رحلتي هي دالاس، تكساس،
where we learned that barbers were not only willing
حيث علمنا أن الحلاقين ليسوا راغبين فقط،
but fully able to roll up their sleeves and participate
بل قادرين تماماً على التشمير عن سواعدهم والمشاركة
in delivering needed health services to improve the health of their customers
في تقديم الخدمات الصحية اللازمة لتحسين صحة زبائنهم
and their community.
ومجتمعاتهم.
We teamed up with an amazing cadre of black barbers
تعاونّا مع كادر رائع من الحلاقين السود
and taught them how to measure blood pressure
وعلمناهم كيفية قياس ضغط الدم
and how to counsel their customers
وكيفية تقديم المشورة لزبائنهم
and refer them to doctors
وإحالتهم إلى الأطباء
to help manage high blood pressure.
ومساعدتهم في علاج ضغط الدم المرتفع.
The barbers were not only willing to do it
لم يرغب الحلاقون في القيام بذلك فقط
but they were damn good at it.
لكنهم كانوا جيدين جداً في ذلك.
Over a three-year period,
على مدى أكثر من ثلاث سنوات،
the barbers measured thousands of blood pressures
قاس الحلاقون الآلاف من ضغوطات الدم
resulting in hundreds of black men being referred to doctors
مما تسبب في إحالة المئات من الرجال السود إلى الأطباء
for medical care of their high blood pressure.
من أجل الرعاية الطبية لإرتفاع ضغط دمهم
These barber-doctor partnerships
علاقات الحلاق بالأطباء هذه
resulted in a 20 percent increase in the number of men
أدت إلى زيادة 20% من عدد الرجال
who were able to achieve target blood pressure levels
الذين كانوا قادرين لتحقيق مستويات ضغط دم معين
and a three-point drop, on average,
وفي المتوسط، تحقق انخفاض بثلاث نقاط
in the blood pressure of each participant.
في ضغط الدم لكل مشترك،
If we were to extrapolate that three point drop
إذا كان في استطاعتنا استقراء أن انخفاض ثلاث نقاط
to every single black man with high blood pressure in America,
لكل رجل أسود يعاني ارتفاعاً في ضغط الدم في أمريكا،
we would prevent 800 heart attacks, 500 strokes and 900 deaths
سنمنع 800 نوبة قلبية و 500 سكتة دماغية و 900 حالة وفاة
from high blood pressure
من ارتفاغ ضغط الدم
in just one year.
في عام واحد فقط.
And our experience with barbershops has been no different in New York City,
وكانت تجربتنا مع الحلاقين في مدينة نيويورك لا تختلف،
where my journey has currently led me.
حيث قادتني رحلتي حالياً.
With an incredible team of diverse research assistants,
مع وجود فريق رائع من مساعدي البحوث المتنوعة،
community health workers and volunteers,
والعاملين في صحة المجتمع والمتطوعيين،
we've been able to partner with over 200 barbershops
كنّا قادرين على المشاركة مع أكثر من 200 صالون حلاقة
and other trusted community venues
وغيرها من الأماكن الموثوق فيها في المجتمع
to reach over 7,000 older black men.
للوصول إلى أكثر من 7000 من الرجال السود من كبار السن.
And we've offered high blood pressure screening and counseling
ووفرنا الفحص والمشورة فيما يتعلق بضغط الدم المرتفع
to each and every one of them.
إلى كل واحد منهم.
Thanks to Denny Moe
بفضل ديني مو
and the myriad other barbers and community leaders
والعدد الهائل من الحلاقين الآخرين وقادة المجتمع
who shared the vision of opportunity and empowerment
الذين تقاسموا رؤية الفرصة والتمكين
to make a difference in their communities,
لإحداث فرق في مجتمعاتهم،
we've been able to not only lower blood pressure
كان في استطاعتنا ليس فقط خفض ضغط الدم
in our participants,
في عدد المشتركين لدينا،
but we've also been able to impact other health indicators.
لكن تمكنا أيضاً في التأثير على مؤشرات صحية أخرى.
So what do you see?
لذلك، فماذا ترون؟
What is your barbershop?
ما هو صالون حلاقتكم؟
Where is that place for you
أين هو ذلك المكان بالنسبة إليكم
where people who are affected by a unique problem
حيث يمكن للناس المتضررين من مشكلة فريدة
can meet a unique solution?
أن يجدوا حلا فريدا؟
When you find that place, see the opportunity.
عندما تجدون هذا المكان، اغتنموا الفرصة.
Thank you.
شكراً لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)